Abhay Chandak

Senior Java Architect at Capgemini

Summary

Working as Senior Java Architect with 25+ years of total experience and 17+ years in IT. Specialties: Proven experience in Java, Angular JS, ReactJS, BackboneJS,BootstrapCSS, HandlebarJS, RequireJS, UnderscoreJS, REST Webservices, Spring MVC, Hazelcast, J2EE, JSP, JQuery, JSF, Drools, Struts, Servlet, Swing, Html, DHTML, Javascript, CSS, AJAX, Hibernate, Springs framework, JAXB, Webservices, Liferay portal, SAAS, ESB, VSS, GlassFish, Websphere8.5, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, JBoss, Pramati Server, Microsoft Project Planner, MySQL 5.0 and SQL Server 2005/2008.

Experience

Senior Java Architect at Capgemini November 2015 - Present

Senior Java Architect

Senior Technology Manager

April 2015 - November 2015 (8 months)

April 2015 till date with Envision Enterprise Solotions Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad as Senior Technical Manager

Environment:

Java, J2EE, JSP, JQuery, JSF, Drools, Html, DHTML, Javascript, CSS, AJAX, AngularJS, Bootstrap, Liferay Portal, Alfresco, Spring and Play Framework Hibernate, Springs framework, Webservices, SAAS, ESB, VSS, GlassFish, Apache Tomcat, Eclipse, Microsoft Product Planner, Oracle 11g and PL SQL 5.0.

Heading a Product based on Shipping and Port Management system.

#

Managing activities pertaining to:

- Planning, designing, High level design, Preparing PMP, integration, code review, client management, team management, Product initiation, scope planning, scope defining, creating work breakdown structure, defining resource activity, estimation, preparing Product plan, risk identification, risk management planning and its mitigation plan, cost estimation, monitoring and

controlling Product, client interaction, closing the Product/requirement of the organization after acceptance test.

- Understanding business requirements from teams like Product, marketing, engagement, sales, operations, customer service. Convert the business requirements to functional requirement specification. Planning with the development team on the architecture and scalability of each feature developed in the system.
- Documenting business requirements, analyzing impact of the changes, preparing functional specifications, technical specifications, developing, configuring and performing unit tests as well as assisting users in the UAT phase.

Product Manager at Hitachi Consulting December 2010 - March 2015 (4 years 4 months)

Heading a product viz., Banking System called as BankON™ which acts as catalyst between ERP System and Bank; BankON support different ERP's like JDEdward 9.0, Oracale 11i, Oracle 12 and Peoplesoft for payroll system. Managing activities pertaining to:

- Planning, designing, integration, code review, client management, team management, product initiation, scope planning, scope defining, creating work breakdown structure, defining resource activity, estimation, preparing project management plan, risk identification, risk management planning and its mitigation plan, cost estimation, monitoring and controlling project, client interaction, closing the product/requirement of the organization after acceptance test.
- Understanding business requirements from teams like product, marketing, engagement, sales, operations, customer service. Convert the business requirements to functional requirement specification. Planning with the development team on the architecture and scalability of each feature developed in the system.
- Documenting business requirements, analyzing impact of the changes, preparing functional specifications, technical specifications, developing, configuring and performing unit tests as well as assisting users in the UAT phase.
- Implementing solutions, advising and supporting system users and business functions.
- Involved in project rollouts and implementations and in improvement projects to facilitate better usage of the system, as well as maintenance and support e-business environments by providing techno functional support of operational business implementations.
- Use-case design architecture and fully responsible for UAT up to production movement. # Handling a team of 18.
- # Webservices for Banking System. ESB application for getting ERP data to BankON.
- # Defined and implemented all the process to be followed within the team and within the organization. Also defined the process to be followed with all different clients.

Associated Vice President

January 2009 - November 2011 (2 years 11 months)

Loyalty Management System is an Loyalty rewards program. User can redeem their points after purchasing any items from any shop or any other media where he is spending. Loyalty Management System is an complex and logically build software which fits for all kind of Partners or customers who ties up with this Loyalty card named as imint.

Sr Product manager

August 2000 - November 2008 (8 years 4 months)

Manager role in project initiation, scope planning, scope defining, scheduling development, creating wbs, budget management, time management, change management, issue/conflict resolution, procurement management, communication management, quality management, testing plans, training plans, proposal management, defining resource activity and estimation, preparing project management plan (PMP), risk identification, risk management planning and its mitigation plan, cost estimation, managing project team, monitoring and controlling project, integration, quality management, client interaction, closing the project/requirement of the client after user acceptance test.

Product Manager

July 1997 - January 2000 (2 years 7 months)

Assigning work and managing a team of 40 staff.

Responsible for designing, manufacturing and quality control of twin core cables and conductors. Organization

Product Engineer

July 1995 - June 1997 (2 years)

Responsible for designing, manufacturing and quality control of power cables.

Product Engineer

April 1994 - May 1995 (1 year 2 months)

Responsible for development and quality control of telecomm kits.

Organization J.T

Lecturer

August 1993 - March 1994 (8 months)

lecturer

Education

Nagpur University

BE, Electrical and Electronics Engineering, 1989 - 1993 Activities and Societies: Debate, Cricket and Table Tennis Nagpur th, BE Electronics, 1988 - 1993

Activities and Societies: Debate, Cricket and Tennis

Nagpur University, Nagpur

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics, 1988 - 1993

Activities and Societies: Participated in Play

Nagpur University

BE, Electronics, Control system, Microprocessor, 1988 - 1992

Abhay Chandak

Senior Java Architect at Capgemini



Contact Abhay on LinkedIn